<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Kyle James Kirwan</title>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Bear Trap Cabin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our adventure group got together for a little snowshoeing out to Bear Trap Cabin, north of Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Trip stats&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Out: 6.3 mi, 3hrs 11mins, 967ft gain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back: 4.5mi, 2hrs 1min, 737ft gain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cvws.icloud-content.com/CAEQARoQx5J6lSitWkXpGWjnKLIPxA/0108ab8191372bce57dba18dc1fa34610de233770f/IMG_0012.jpg?v=0&amp;z=https://p48-content.icloud.com:443&amp;x=1&amp;a=BgDgZXOI7EY3vsFiaxu8vGyEY7mOA5iVOgEAAA%3D%3D&amp;e=1492666986000&amp;r=f33fdfe3-9744-4e8c-87c5-bdad3a717707-4&amp;c=&amp;s=EeNinCj9vzumxqjWGWY4tk21A78&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; We decided to bring a &quot;pulk&quot; along, which was a terrible idea. They probably work well for flat terrain, but dragging it up 1000ft of gain in a day was painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cvws.icloud-content.com/CAEQARoQx5J6lSitWkXpGWjnKLIPxA/0165d67680bf4c4691c6860fb929bcd686977c1676/IMG_0005.jpg?v=0&amp;z=https://p48-content.icloud.com:443&amp;x=1&amp;a=BmdmDVwxYA8YlWTg%2FHq6c9Gs8T3oA5iVOgEAAA%3D%3D&amp;e=1492666986000&amp;r=f33fdfe3-9744-4e8c-87c5-bdad3a717707-22&amp;c=&amp;s=tZre0CalZlycaazE8LFht_mnDQs&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; The cabin was mostly covered in snow. It's 2 stories tall, but this was all you could see sticking out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cvws.icloud-content.com/CAEQARoQx5J6lSitWkXpGWjnKLIPxA/0157f0925d787a2c90813523a906bb3344f8c52609/IMG_0007.jpg?v=0&amp;z=https://p48-content.icloud.com:443&amp;x=1&amp;a=BhJDWXmyK9H%2FXUVz10sVTOQ%2BPRAGA5iVOgEAAA%3D%3D&amp;e=1492666986000&amp;r=f33fdfe3-9744-4e8c-87c5-bdad3a717707-18&amp;c=&amp;s=zpUhZ-EXPn2zoW_eSCiROavTq_I&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; The inside of the cabin was totally dark. Fortunately it was well stocked with firewood, candles, and canned food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cvws.icloud-content.com/CAEQARoQx5J6lSitWkXpGWjnKLIPxA/016fabb239ddb4b4bc59d857c88c1a10c74245dab4/IMG_0006.jpg?v=0&amp;z=https://p48-content.icloud.com:443&amp;x=1&amp;a=BoA841npNhFTYPLxEOZtLy0bpi%2FtA5iVOgEAAA%3D%3D&amp;e=1492666986000&amp;r=f33fdfe3-9744-4e8c-87c5-bdad3a717707-12&amp;c=&amp;s=MHlkKqHFlYhwYPyU88EsYib-Njk&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; Once we dug out the cabin, Megan collected snow in a bucket that we could melt for drinking and cooking water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cvws.icloud-content.com/CAEQARoQx5J6lSitWkXpGWjnKLIPxA/011f1ed623fa43e8df30c284b39c615a6403678111/IMG_0001.jpg?v=0&amp;z=https://p48-content.icloud.com:443&amp;x=1&amp;a=Bmyggp8RDRxoxKoNikX9Eq%2F%2Bsxr0A5iVOgEAAA%3D%3D&amp;e=1492666986000&amp;r=f33fdfe3-9744-4e8c-87c5-bdad3a717707-25&amp;c=&amp;s=V2kyK5sZekEfkNOVYxFuhDCbj_w&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; The hike back felt significantly shorter than the one out. Going downhill with the pulk was easier...but I still wouldn't have brought it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/bear-trap-cabin.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/19/bear-trap-cabin.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>My recent reading list</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The books I've been reading in the last several months, roughly in reverse order of completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Child of God&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;By Cormac McCarthy. Relatively short but thoroughly enjoyable. The only other McCarthy book I've read was The Road, which was the first book I cried at. This was less crushing, but still felt like watching a car accident happen in slow motion. Themes and imagery are heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Child-Vintage-International-Cormac-McCarthy-ebook/dp/B003XT60I6/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1489995825&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=a+child+of+god&quot;&gt;Child of God on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;The Innovator's Dilemma&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;By Clayton Christenson. This was recommended to me by a mentor of mine, who I respect greatly, so it went to the top of my list. It was described to me as &quot;here is my theory, and 15 examples that prove it's true&quot;, which sounds like a common theme among business writing. While the description was accurate, the theory proposed was convincing. Even if it isn't correct, it seems like having a flawed framework for dealing with change is better than not having one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Innovators-Dilemma-Technologies-Management-Innovation-ebook/dp/B00E257S86/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1489996527&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=innovators+dilemma&quot;&gt;The Innovator's Dilemma on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Structures&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;By J.E. Gordon. A very approachable explanation of the basic forces behind buildings, bridges, and other structures that we live with daily. I loved the blending of history, physics concepts, simple-enough equations, and humor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Structures-Things-Dont-Fall-Down/dp/0306812835/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1489995451&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=structures+or+why+things+don%27t+fall+down&quot;&gt;Structures on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;By Jason Fried. An ultra-concise detailing of the practices used at 37 Signals (now Basecamp) for becoming the multi-billion dollar startup they are to...ah nevermind, they're still a small business and like it that way. While the book has ideas that push startups to think about what really matters, and is worth the short read, I'm tired of the 37 Signals &quot;any business who prioritizes growth is stupid&quot; diatribe. The shadow of that bias hung over me while reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rework-Jason-Fried-ebook/dp/B002MUAJ2A/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1489996389&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=rework&quot;&gt;Rework on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 17:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/19/recentReadingList.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/19/recentReadingList.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Recap of a quiet weekend</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Rock climbing&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My first time top roping in a long time. We went to Mission Cliffs where I &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; aced the belay test. I forgot how to check my double figure eight knot (look for 5 sets of parallel lines). I climbed some 5.10d's and a 5.11a. It was a good wake up call that bouldering focuses on very different strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;A walk&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Megan and I walked 9 miles in one day. We hit Buena Vista, Corona Heights, and Sutro Open Space Preserve. I was fortunate enough to have Apple Pay set up on my phone so we could buy something to drink in Cole Valley, as I forgot my wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Reading Kafka&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I borrowed &lt;em&gt;The Trial&lt;/em&gt;, by F. Kafka, from my friend George. I was surprised to have covered 70 pages in one day (the book is ~250). I've been mixing paperback (Hillbilly Elegy) and Kindle books (The Innovator's Dilemma) recently. Each format has different qualities to appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 17:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/12/weekend-journal.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/12/weekend-journal.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Driving Death Valley</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-11.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November of 2016 we decided to go to Death Valley for Thanksgiving. For the past few years we had been going to a tango festival up in Oregon, but it was canceled. Good time to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;First day - Hot Springs&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We rented a rented Jeep, picked up two of our traveler friends, and met up with two more who were in their own truck (a Toyota FJ). We headed out of San Francisco towards Tahoe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-1.jpg&quot;&gt;
Megan kept us happy with her ukelele songs on the way up through Tahoe. From there we headed south, past Topaz and Mono Lakes and eventually into the valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We slept near some hot springs that we enjoyed before bedtime. The air was probably in the upper 20s F by this point, but the water was perfectly warm. We made dinner as the temperature continued dropping. My bag is rated for 30F, so with a low of 7F that night, I was pretty uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-2.jpg&quot;&gt;
The morning view from a pile of rocks near our campsite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-3.jpg&quot;&gt;
Our two mules bearing their foodstuffs and gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Second day - Into the Valley&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-4.jpg&quot;&gt;
As we entered the valley we had to air down our tires for better traction and a softer ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-5.jpg&quot;&gt;
Making our way into Saline Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-6.jpg&quot;&gt;
We stopped for lunch near a collection of other people's camping vehicles in Saline Valley. This one demanded its own picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-7.jpg&quot;&gt;
As it was getting dark, we had to decide whether to make camp here, near a salt lake with some strange wood remnants of a cable-drawn bucket system, or head further up toward the Lippincott Mine road. We decided to press on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Third day - Mines and the Racetrack&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first thing to tackle today was Lippincott pass. It's a long stretch of uphill road wide enough for one vehicle. The road itself is a pile of tennis ball-sized rocks, so we made use of the 2-speed transfer case on our Jeep, keeping it in &quot;4-lo&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-8.jpg&quot;&gt;
After we cleared the pass, we had to document our achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, we went to examine some abandoned mines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-9.jpg&quot;&gt;
We spent a lot of time after the trip identifying this vehicle. I think it was a 1930's Buick. The gear shifter still moved through each gear smoothly (given the condition anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-10.jpg&quot;&gt;
A warning at the entrance to the King Lead mine, at the end of Lippincott Mine road. It reads about snakes, unfired explosives, cave-ins, and how the park rangers will not be saving you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the mines, we progressed to Racetrack Playa, a common Death Valley point of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-11.jpg&quot;&gt;
The Grandstand on the Racetrack Playa. It contrasts so heavily with the almost-white and sandless floor of the playa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-12.jpg&quot;&gt;
Two friends leaning into the wind blowing on the playa floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-13.jpg&quot;&gt;
The floor of the playa was almost leatherlike. Smooth but firm, with no sand on it at all. It would crack slightly under the pressure of your bare feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we slept at the most pedestrian site of the trip -- a plain campground near a gift shop and gas station in the valley. To preserve as much of the &quot;outdoorness&quot; as possible, we moved our tents far from the fire ring, in between bunches of shoulder-height sand dunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Last day - A hike before home&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-14.jpg&quot;&gt;
We hiked in this canyon on the last day before heading out. We got back out just as rain started coming down -- something we didn't want to be in the canyon for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/death_valley/death_valley-15.jpg&quot;&gt;
We wanted to climb the Panamint dunes visble in the lower left of the background, but the detour would've put us back home later than we wanted. We settled for this picture instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death Valley has cemented its place in my list of great locations in California. It's a rewarding trip, especially if you're willing to go down some of the many less traveled roads available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 14:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/12/death-valley.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/12/death-valley.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Tilden Little Farm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We went to a little farm in Berkeley called Tilden Little Farm. You can bring your own lettuce or celery and feed the animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/000052490031.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; These cows had long tongues which reach out to take the lettuce from your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/000052490037.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; Geese...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/83326/kylejameskirwan.com_rsources/photography/000052490033.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image-big&quot;&gt; These piglets were fun. They run around like puppies, occasionally looking for a teat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 09:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/26/tilden-little-farm.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/02/26/tilden-little-farm.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
