<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Kyle James Kirwan</title>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>8 Simple Data Quality Checks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who's spent much time working with analytics data has run into a data quality issue at some point -- sometimes obvious and temporary, other times subtle and undetected for weeks or months. This post reviews some basic data quality failure cases and the SQL-based tests you can run to monitor for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This topic was inpsired by two observations I made while leading product on Uber's internal data quality platform:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lion's share of quality problems discovered by hand (usually triggering a fire for the discoverer) could be caught with simple and boring tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most teams blanked when they opened up the data quality tool for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We often broke the write's block with a simple review of their table and basic tests that they could  -- so I've compiled some common test categories that anyone can use to get started covering their analytics data with test coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In future posts I plan cover some more complex tests, including between-table tests, and cross-datacenter comparisons.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Too many or too few rows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest case is to check that any rows exist — which may not be necessary for commonly accessed tables, but might be helpful to use on lookup tables that get looked at by ETLs more than by humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a partitioned table you can also check that each partition has a sane number of rows (e.g. in a time-partitioned table compare today’s count to the trailing N-day average count) to guard against missing or partially-loaded partitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;WITH
date_counts AS (
  SELECT
    date_partition,
    COUNT(*) AS cnt_rows
  FROM my_table
  WHERE date_partition &amp;gt;= NOW()::DATE - INTERVAL '6 days'
  GROUP BY date_partition),

lst_date_stats AS (
  SELECT cnt_rows
  FROM date_counts
  WHERE date_partition = NOW()::DATE - INTERVAL '1 days'),

prev_5day_stats AS (
  SELECT
    AVERAGE(cnt_rows) + (3 * STDDEV(cnt_rows)) AS cnt_rows_upper_bnd,
    AVERAGE(cnt_rows) - (3 * STDDEV(cnt_rows)) AS cnt_rows_lower_bnd
  FROM date_counts
  WHERE date_partition &amp;lt; NOW()::DATE - INTERVAL '1 day')

SELECT
  cnt_rows &amp;lt; cnt_rows_low_bnd AS is_cnt_rows_low,
  cnt_rows &amp;gt; cnt_rows_up_bnd AS is_cnt_rows_high
FROM lst_date_stats JOIN prev_5day_stats ON TRUE
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Unexpected NULLs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always wise to check for any nulls in columns that are meant to never have them (e.g. a user_uuid) as this can wreak serious havoc on ETLs, queries, etc. like causing cartesian-product explosions from joining NULLs to NULLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT COUNT(*)
FROM my_table
WHERE my_column IS NULL
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For data which is expected to be null occasionally (e.g. a field that didn’t exist several app versions ago) another test can make sense — &lt;em&gt;but beware&lt;/em&gt; — you are now doing crude anomaly detection. Your alert may no longer indicate bad data, but unexpected user behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  ROUND(COUNT(CASE WHEN my_column IS NULL THEN 1 END) / COUNT(*), 2) * 100 AS pct_null
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Duplicates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially true with IDs and UUIDs, it can be important to not have duplicates for some types of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WARNING: this check can be especially expensive to run on large datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;WITH uuid_cnts AS (
SELECT
  my_uuid, COUNT(*) AS cnt_freq
FROM my_table
GROUP BY my_uuid)

SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN cnt_freq &amp;gt; 1 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_duplicates
FROM uuid_cnts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Implied types&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes (often for historical reasons) you may find yourself with one &lt;em&gt;implied&lt;/em&gt; type (say an integer) stored in a column that has a different &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; type (say a string). Testing that the data is actually an integer, as you expect it to be, can save you if some unexpectedly typed values start appearing — especially if this column is fed into a model or application that can break if there’s a deviation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Regex credited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/9043551/regex-match-integer-only&quot;&gt;this Stack thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN REGEXP_INSTR(string_of_ints, '^([+-]?[1-9]\d*|0)$') = 0 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_invalid_integers
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UUIDs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Regex credited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/136505/searching-for-uuids-in-text-with-regex#6640851&quot;&gt;this Stack thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN REGEXP_INSTR(user_uuid, '^(\+\d{1,2}\s)?\(?\d{3}\)?[\s.-]\d{3}[\s.-]\d{4}$') = 0 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_invalid_email
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Formatted strings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cousin of the &lt;em&gt;Implied Types&lt;/em&gt; check, you can use regexes to look for improper email addresses, phone numbers, etc. that are stored in string fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email addresses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Regex credited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://emailregex.com&quot;&gt;emailregex.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN REGEXP_INSTR(email_address, '^[A-Z0-9._%-]+@[A-Z0-9.-]+\.[A-Z]{2,4}$') = 0 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_invalid_email
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phone numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Regex credited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/16699007/regular-expression-to-match-standard-10-digit-phone-number#16699507&quot;&gt;this Stack thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN REGEXP_INSTR(phone_number, '^(\+\d{1,2}\s)?\(?\d{3}\)?[\s.-]\d{3}[\s.-]\d{4}$') = 0 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_invalid_phone
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US ZIP Codes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Regex credited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/a/7185241/1709587&quot;&gt;this Stack thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN REGEXP_INSTR(zip_code, '\d{5}([ \-]\d{4})?') = 0 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_invalid_zip
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit Card Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;NOTE: Looks for continuous numbers with no spaces or delimiters between.
Regex credited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/a/7185241/1709587&quot;&gt;this Stack thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN REGEXP_INSTR(cc_number, '^(?:4[0-9]{12}(?:[0-9]{3})?|[25][1-7][0-9]{14}|6(?:011|5[0-9][0-9])[0-9]{12}|3[47][0-9]{13}|3(?:0[0-5]|[68][0-9])[0-9]{11}|(?:2131|1800|35\d{3})\d{11})$') = 0 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_cc_number
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Enums&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know all values that should be allowed in the field, you may want to be alerted when something new shows up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT COUNT(*)
FROM my_table
WHERE my_column NOT IN (enum_1, enum_2, enum_3)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Timestamps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If some timestamps should always occur before others (e.g. created-at and updated-at) you can check for out-of-order timestamps for each step in your funnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN timestamp_2 &amp;lt; timestamp_1 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_ooo_a,
  COUNT(CASE WHEN timestamp_3 &amp;lt; timestamp_2 THEN 1 END) AS cnt_ooo_b
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also check for timestamps created in the future, or too far in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT
  COUNT(CASE WHEN timestamp &amp;gt;= NOW() + INTERVAL '1 minute' THEN 1 END) AS cnt_future_ts,
  COUNT(CASE WHEN timestamp &amp;lt;= NOW() - INTERVAL '5 years' THEN 1 END) AS cnt_ancient_ts
FROM my_table
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Numerics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing these sometimes requires more granular knowledge of your product/business logic, but can alert you when reality deviates from that theoretical logic. Check that non-zero numbers are positive, that mins and maxes are correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT COUNT(*)
FROM my_table
WHERE my_column &amp;lt; min_value
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT COUNT(*)
FROM my_table
WHERE my_column &amp;gt; max_value
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: It’s easy to start using these as crude anomaly detection tools — if you do this be sure to indicate clearly for your teammates which respond to business behavior and which respond to damaged data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to get started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do it all yourself, set up the queries as jobs on a DAG orchestrator (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://airflow.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Airflow&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://luigi.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&quot;&gt;Luigi&lt;/a&gt;), then connect that to your notification channels (Slack, Pagerduty, etc.). Easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want to get going faster, sign up for &lt;a href=&quot;https://torodata.io/&quot;&gt;Toro Data Quality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Toro makes it easy to deploy tests in minutes, and saves your data engineering team the overhead of maintaining a reliable test orchestrator. All you need to start is a read-only account on your database or warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Other posts you may enjoy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Between-table tests (coming soon!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-datacenter testing (coming soon!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anomaly detection vs. data-damage detection (coming soon!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/data_quality_tests_you_should_know.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/data_quality_tests_you_should_know.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Startup School Notes: How to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My notes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xZi4kTJG-LE&quot;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the process Clever used to get to first $1M in revenue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When talking to a customer (ever): shut up and listen to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Founders do sales, ideally it's 1 person's full time job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expect to hear &quot;no&quot; a lot, prepare for a 2.5% conversion rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your network for your first few sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to conferences, use them as a sales channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow up religiously, can take months to close a deal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch out for 3 hangups when closing the deal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your sales model and pricing model are intertwined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Who does sales&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do! The Don Draper imagery is bullshit…you can sell, you need to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clever had 3 cofounders and decided that 1 person had to own sales every day. The other two spent all their time building the product. He started selling before the product was actually built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be as much of a full-time job as you can make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;As a founder you should always be doing 1 of 2 things:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building the product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talking to users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Understanding your users is core to sales.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must understand your users in order to sell to them. Your goal is to learn and solve their problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;As a founder you have unique advantages for sales.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passion for the product and business, more than anyone else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry expertise, you know this problem in and out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The funnel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prospecting: finding leads, who is interested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversations: is this right for them or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closing: completing the actual transaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promised land: revenue comes in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Part 1: Prospecting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll hear no a lot, this is ok. Here's why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology adoption curve describes 5 stages: innovators, early adopt, majority, late, and laggards. The innovators segment is estimated to be only 2.5% of the &quot;population&quot; you're selling to. This means you need to find 100 companies to get 2-3 sales. Expect that you'll need to grind hard to get those early sales, you can't get by with 2-4 contacts, you'll need 100s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Part 2: Conversations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Use your network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder's personal networks are almost always the earliest deals, these are the best and the easiest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Go to conferences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small ones not the big ones. These are usually only a few days in a hotel meeting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to go where your users are, and your users may be going to meet their peers at these. Ask your customers what conferences they go to and pick a few to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These can be a few $k each ticket, so...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the list of attendees and know who’s gonna be there&lt;/strong&gt;, write to organizer if necessary, don’t just show up. Email these people in advance, ask if they’ll have time to chat. Do this with as many people as possible. Aim for entire day booked in 30 minute increments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cold emails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the highest volume method, but many people don’t know how to do it well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad&lt;/strong&gt; Long, not personalized, not actionable, boring, irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good&lt;/strong&gt; Short, concise, personalized, actionable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Format: this might be relevant to you because of some personalized reasons, even if you’re not looking I’d love to talk to you about it, if you have time this week or next please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;You’re on the phone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHUT UP AND LISTEN!&lt;/strong&gt; They should be doing 70% of the talking (this is the most important thing ever).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales is about listening. The battering ram approach does not work. Build a relationship and understand their problems, find out how you can help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When talking:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t practice points, practice questions for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uber-conference: a tool to see how much time you each spent talking during the call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Actual steps from a real deal at Clever&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This took 2 months, and landed a $100k/yr customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Met in person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (no response)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (no response)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schedule a call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flow 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (no response), email (no response), email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schedule next call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pricing call #1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pricing call #2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent a quote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answer questions via email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send contract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send references&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send financials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (no response)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redlines #1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email nudge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redline #2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redline #3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redline #4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call with CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redline #5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It’s not over until they actually say “no”
Being persistent isn’t rude, they’re busy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Getting a “no”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick no is a blessing in disguise
Worst thing is dragging it out and wasting time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Part 3: Closing (enterprise)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They said they wanna buy, great.&lt;br/&gt;
Many deals get messed up here though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3 things to watch out for:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redlining: They will want to change the agreement, redlining. Be ready to send the agreement immediately. Don’t fight over dumb shit, get it done: early customers are mana from heaven, don’t quibble, they will want some weird random shit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid one-more-feature closing trap, unless it’s customer 1 or 2, this is most often a pass (there is usually actually more than 1 more thing). Can offer that we will build if we hear multiple customers need it, sometimes they will still take this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free trials. You need commitment, validation, and revenue. Free trials are the opposite of this. We spent a lot of time building the product and doing the sale, cannot afford to give it for free. But we know there is risk and we understand. We only do annual agreements but if you cancel in the first 30 days, we’ll let you go. This creates a default-yes situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sales method is intertwined with your pricing model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Five ways to get to $1M in sales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$1,000,000 customer, only need 1!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$100,000 customers, only need  10!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$10,000 customers, only need 100!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$1,000 customers, need 1000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Is your sales pipeline appropriate relative to your pricing?
If 1-2 then great, high-touch sales makes sense
If 3-4 then need to find more standard, low friction, maybe self-serve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What’s the right time between email follow ups?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little under a week, 5-6-7 days later is polite and not over-eager&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When do you feel like you’re pestering?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think, if they haven’t said no, you’re right to follow up
If you’ve followed up 8 times…take the hint
But assume the best and that they’re busy, you’re not the top priority
Keep the emails thoughtful and personalized &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;— important&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When you’re getting early no’s, how to tell product-market-fit issue?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t discover it from the no’s, only from jesses. Too many reasons you could be getting a no. The states reason is often not honest, so ignore this, they’re being polite. Your signal is if you can’t get any yesses ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When prospecting, better for big names or easier closes?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YC gives advice of breadth-first search. Optimize for speed, a customer is better than nothing. Talk to the big ones though, might be surprised. Who needs it the most, they’ll be fastest. In early days don’t need big logos, just need validation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How did you learn your pricing?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We guessed…but we got feedback quickly from the market. Most startup founders go too low. Pick a number, try to close a sale, try doubling it next time! Why was the first sale $100k? We picked a number…“THIS IS THE RIGHT PRICE! NO OTHER PRICE WOULD BE FAIR!”…but be willing to quickly iterate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How do you bootstrap sales with $50/mo?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You basically shouldn’t do any of these things. You need marketing, not sales. Email campaigns, self-service signup, etc. OR: raise the price where sales makes sense&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What if there aren’t enough case studies to show off?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many founders think they never have enough to convince people. We didn't have them early on, it's fine, just sell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/20/howtosell.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/12/20/howtosell.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What does it take to be a PM?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;The question&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following question has been posed to me several times over the last few years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did you get started as a PM and how can I do it too?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite a few of the people doing the asking have turned PM themselves, and some are probably better at it now than I am! I'd like to think my advice here helped someone get from 0 to 1 (if imperfectly) so I'm encouraged to put it out there for others to find, in case there are truly some nuggets of wisdom in here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Article breakdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you start as a PM?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I show the skills, talents, and desire to be a successful PM?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommended reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;1. How did you start as pm?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working as a data scientist on Uber's Growth team, I wound up running the company's first AB tests. Fast forward a bit (many more tests and a lot of self-directed learning about experimentation theory and practice), I was offered the &quot;subject matter expert&quot; role on the newly formed team tasked with building the internal AB testing platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PM and I wound up working famously well together: I knew the audience and what they needed from the product, and he knew how to take a team from 0 to cranking out a high quality and well-loved product. Two years later, our products had been adopted by hundreds of teams across the business to run thousands of concurrent experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here comes the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to a new team but in a similar role: they had a PM and I was to be the data science expert. The new PM was juggling several projects at once and was stretched, presenting some opportunities to pick up work he wasn't able to do. I jumped on these opportunities, applying my best imitations of techniques I watched my former PM use to get my old team started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not long after, our new PM decided to move off our project to focus on some of his other demands. I was offered to step into the gap by our team's product director. Within a month I got offered to help out with a second team that wanted some product thinking to improve the coherency of the tools they were building. I tried replicating these techniques there as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months and some product and feature launches later, I presented my accomplishments in a round of internal interviews with senior product folks from around the company. Succeeding those interviews gave me the official title, though it was the six months of experiences that made me truly feel like a product manager (of course, with a lot to learn).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;2. How do I show the skills, talents, and desire to be a successful PM?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we'll go through 4 categories of skills, then talk talent and desire, then summarize how to think through interview prep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Skill 1: Product strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the highest level thinking about the team’s raison d’etre and how they will succeed in 3 months, 1 year, 5 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the fundamental problem needing to be solved? Mess this up and you're wasting the company's money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a picture of the customer(s). What are their needs, their goals, their limits, and their strengths?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to go from 0 product to version 1? (very difficult)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to iterate from 1 to 2 to N? (a little easier)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to measure the product success, which metrics and why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to deal with competing solutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to sell the product and get adoption from your target users?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to prioritize the steps to solve this problem? You can do anything but you can’t do everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to tell the story of your product: why does it deserve to exist, what matters in the next (or first) version and what can you save for later, what is the long term / magic-wand vision you’re ultimately aiming for? How will you make this simple enough, and sexy enough, to get people to understand your vision and feel excited about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Skill 2: Product design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is solution thinking part 1, what should the solution do, look like, and feel like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to work with user researchers to clarify user needs and broad categories of solutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to work with designers to explore possible solutions, then refine one into a buildable product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with modern design options, trends, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to approach mobile vs. desktop vs. hardware vs. sales-materials/copy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Skill 3: Technical knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is solution thinking part 2, how will we build the designed solution feasibly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software architecture: how are your team's engineers proposing to build this product? What are the components and how do they work together?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to work with the engineering manager to align the needs of the product with the strengths and desires of the engineers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will you get estimates for the engineering time? How much safety factor do you need to pad these estimates with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the technical limitations and strengths of different approaches to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying on top of new technologies so your product strategy reflects what’s possible today and will be possible soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Skill 4: Empathy and people management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constantly and vitally important, these are the skills for making (all of) the various humans involved in your organization do what needs to get done for your vision to succeed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to manage your own team keeping productivity and morale high, celebrating successes and recovering from failures?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to manage sideways interacting with other teams to avoid dependency problems, align timelines, avoid duplicate work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to manage upwards interacting with your boss and other leaders to show successes and get resources for your team, get their support to prevent future problems with other teams?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;You superpowers and your defense-zones&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do you excel, where do you invest, and what's on hold?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do a really critical self evaluation to understand which of these 4 skill areas is currently your “superpower” that makes you a special PM that kicks ass at a particular scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need to know which areas are your defense-zones. Which areas do you want to strengthen, and which other areas will (consciously!) remain weak while you invest your time in strengthening them? Why are those the right investments for you to be making, based on what you want to do with your career (e.g. someone who wants to make the next iPhone may care more about product design, someone who wants to build the next Stripe may care more about strategy and technical, etc.)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Talent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe &quot;talent&quot; really just means &quot;a skill I've stumbled into practicing without realizing it&quot;, but this is my closest answer for what &quot;talent&quot; a PM should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the unique strengths of a PM (stronger in a PM vs. any other role) is ability to take a vague question and distill it into a story that can both clarify AND inspire. A vague question like “tell me about your favorite product” might turn into: who is the audience for this product, what are their needs, where is the product strong, where does it need improvement, what are it’s major competitors or analogues?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to break things down and create structure where there is none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Desire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even if you’re not the best PM yet, convince me that someday you will be, and that I want you on my team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s a story you can tell about a situation where doing “PM” work really made you happy and energized? What motivates you and makes PM the right path for you vs. data science vs. design vs. engineering vs. …? (I’m bored of engineering is not a great answer to this, there are a thousand other things you could do that aren’t engineering…why this one?) What projects or research or other outputs have to done that actually showcase this desire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to prepare&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To succeed in interviews you will need to have thought through, and excel at explaining how you embody the above concepts, clearly and concisely, to an interviewer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a list of the questions you’re likely to face. Set a target amount of time you have to answer each question (2 minutes? 3?) and hone your answers (not word for word, but know the crux of your responses).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After feeling comfortable with your answers, actually sit down and say it to someone. For the best feedback, video your &quot;interview&quot; with that persion...your weaknesses will immediately become visible and you can work on them. You talk too fast, you jumble things and the story is hard to follow, you go blank and can’t answer, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;3. Recommended readings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People&lt;/strong&gt; seems hokey but has some real wisdom in it. You are ultimately responsible for your own successes and failures. Only you can kick your own ass into getting things going the way you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPRINT&lt;/strong&gt; is about how to do rapid product design explorations, and get user feedback to tell you which of your ideas is stupid and which have some traction. I’ve done this, in real life, with real people. It works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cracking the PM Interview&lt;/strong&gt; is quick cheat sheet for prepping for interviews, common questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovators Dilemma&lt;/strong&gt; shows how businesses do or don't succeed when it comes to evolving their strategies and products. This will inform your perspective of where you add value to a bigger organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radical Focus&lt;/strong&gt; is about setting good goals, which &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; important and &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; difficult to do well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Next up!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really just my stream of thought while sitting in a Philz in La Jolla. To fill in the gaps and refine this further, I should contact some strong PMs I know and hear how they think about this question, and maybe even get their review of my answer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 07:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/16/pm_skills.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/11/16/pm_skills.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Notes: Music for Tango DJ's Seminar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a dump of the notes I took during a DJ seminar given by a well respected west coast DJ several years ago. I hope to come back and clean them up, but here they are as they were written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Class One - Musical Quality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Positioning of the beat Emphasis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;End (like the bando) vs beginning (piano)
Emphasis of the beat can be used to build families of tango sounds
x = energy, y = rythm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Street band&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centered emphasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loose, sweet feeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canaro, Victor, Lomuto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;El Adios (Canaro) for example&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Driving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forward emphasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feels pushy, tight, angry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DArienzo, Biagi, some Troilo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Refined&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rear emphasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feels laggy, elegant, and melancholy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DAgostino, Di Sarli, Fresedo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Exploratory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely late emphasis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretchy, virutosic, angsty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;De Caro, Pugliese, some Laurenz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;The Backbone&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calo: Refined&lt;br/&gt;
DiSarli: Centered&lt;br/&gt;
Troilo: Driving, Exploratory&lt;br/&gt;
Pugliese: Exploratoy&lt;br/&gt;
DArienzo: Driving&lt;br/&gt;
Canaro: Street Band&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Side Players&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DAgostino&lt;br/&gt;
De caro&lt;br/&gt;
Biagi&lt;br/&gt;
Rodriguez&lt;br/&gt;
Lomuto&lt;br/&gt;
Fresedo&lt;br/&gt;
DAngelis: hard to place, sometimes multiple styles even in same song&lt;br/&gt;
Demare: Refined, Exploratory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Equipment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Speaker positioning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers should be above head height &lt;br/&gt;
Should be along the long end of the floor so sound is distributed&lt;br/&gt;
Pointed slightly in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Mixer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your sound levels all below 75% (source? Research this)&lt;br/&gt;
Make sure bass isn’t turned up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Volume&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check volume on floor frequently&lt;br/&gt;
Before you start, check for loud or quiet areas&lt;br/&gt;
Watch number of dancers, sound will be muffled if there are a lot of dancers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Equalizer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the pops and scratches on are on the higher frequencies&lt;br/&gt;
Most of the song data is in the midranges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Class Two - Music and Space&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Last week's topics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;where the emphasis lies on the beat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mapping the orchestras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talked about emotional content linked to type of sound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;key instruments

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;streetband - bass, low tones of violins, focus on keeping the beat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exploratory - bando&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refined - piano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;driving - bando(?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;How to put these classifiers to work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Group songs with a similar sound so dancers know what they can expect.
Dancers can pair based on what emotion they want to express given the theme of the tanda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Role of the DJ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help the dancers express the music.&lt;br/&gt;
To have them leave the floor feeling confident.&lt;br/&gt;
Keeping a balance so that everyone has something to dance to.&lt;br/&gt;
Sequencing the songs in a way that flows and feels sensible.&lt;br/&gt;
To bring them through key musical areas so they feel the entire range of &quot;the milonga experience&quot;. &lt;br/&gt;
To keep the early dancers happy even while warming up the dancers who arrive later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Thinking about the tanda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A song is the atomic unit.&lt;br/&gt;
A tanda is the molecule.&lt;br/&gt;
Each atom has a specific feeling to contribute to the molecule.&lt;br/&gt;
The tanda should elicit a specific feeling which grows and progresses from song 1 to 4.&lt;br/&gt;
Each tanda needs to fit the flow of the night, blending smoothly from the previous one and into the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tanda Skeleton&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Very familiar / well known&lt;br/&gt;
Draws dancers to the floor&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;El Cencerro&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pensalo Bien&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tristeza Marina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Vamos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Araca La Cana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Adios Buenos Aires&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Well known, almost on par with song 1&lt;br/&gt;
Danceable but not appropriate for beginning or ending&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Gorriones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Caero Al As&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sencillo y Compadre&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Less familiar, good place to experiment (slightly)&lt;br/&gt;
Continues or revises direction&lt;br/&gt;
Higher energy than song 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Also very familiar
Highest energy&lt;br/&gt;
Has a strong ending, can feature a varacion or a nice vocal&lt;br/&gt;
Makes them feel confidence and lets them express their emotion  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;El Recodo (might be a good opener, but too powerful, nothing could go up from here)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dime Mi Amor (voice at the end is nice)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;La Capilla Blanca (slow down at the end doesn't affect any &quot;next song&quot;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Patetico (nice variacion)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Things to think about&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The start and the end are the most important, people remember these

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;primacy and recency effect in psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity and variety should be balanced

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;too many familiar songs is boring and tired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;too much variety is bothersome, even if all the songs are danceable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the middle of the set is a good place to introduce less known music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;listening to your collection TOO MUCH may throw off your feeling of what is familiar within the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guide the change in energy within the tanda

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should travel in a specific direction - the goal of the tanda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the intensity of the direction should increase over the tanda, not fall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;direction can be romance, intensity, virtuosity, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;does not ALL need to be moving upward, but last two should&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;could go down on the second song (forms a checkmark shape)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't get in the way of the tanda being danceable just to explore as a DJ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't leave a slow ending on a song in the middle, it will interfere with the next song's energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Same singer &amp;amp; orchestra is usually best

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changing will alert some dancers, taking them out of the moment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can change orchestras if there's a very specific reason&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can mix instrumental / vocal (vocal often has higher intensity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Varacion usually in Song 4 but can be in others if they feel right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch out for songs involving soccor in the lyrics, can be distracting to spanish speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;The SuperTanda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The molecular chain&lt;br/&gt;
TTM or TTV - As a unit, lower energy tango to higher energy tango&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Space - The Ronda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rectangle provides opportunity for different movement based on side length&lt;br/&gt;
Square can feel more consistent to some dancers&lt;br/&gt;
Permeate tables to allow more entry / exit points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to watch the room&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blur your vision and perceive the flow, are there big gaps or concentrations?&lt;br/&gt;
If people are focused on specific musical elements or movements too much, it suggests they aren't feeling the music and their partner enough.&lt;br/&gt;
D'Arienzo: forces them to adhere to the beat&lt;br/&gt;
Pugliese / Podesta: allows them to focus inward and on each other&lt;br/&gt;
Watch for temperature&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If the room is hot, don't make them move enough to heat it up more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If the room is cold, make them move around and warm it up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Homework for Class 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose 3 songs that represent tandas
Build a SuperTanda and justify it (TTM or TTV)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Class Three - The Supertanda&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example tanda - builds rythmic intensity&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dejame Ser Asi - Llorar por una mujer - Danza Maligna - En la buena y la mala&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example tanda - builds melodic emotional intensity&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tristeza Marina - Decime que paso - Charlemos - Griseta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad Example tanda - nice songs but doesn't feel like it progresses&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A Quien La Puede Importar - Esta Noche en Buenos Aires - Gorriones - El Yacare&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad Example tanda - &quot;wakes up&quot; the dancers&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Santa Milonguita - Trago Amargo - Infamia - Dime mi amor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switches singer, recodring quality, pianist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is ok to do as long as the voices are similar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tanturri, Troilo, Di Sarli should be left alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mixing Beron might be dicey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to the first and last song to check that there's a progression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to the entire song, they might get weird halfway in - A Pan y Agua&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Role of the DJ - Revisted&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitate the &quot;milonga experience&quot;&lt;br/&gt;
Curating the experience through the music&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drawing dancers to the floor - Grab a sitter and make them dance with you to break the ice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping the dancers express the music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping them navigate through the night, including the change in skill level as the night progresses - Easy / danceable early - gooey center - touching the musical corners toward the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help them feel the music deeply, focusing on an instrument or sound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;RULE: Don't get in the way of the dancers, you're a step ahead of them but not controlling them&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having supertandas built is helpful&lt;br/&gt;
Example: &lt;em&gt;Di Sarli / Rufino -&gt; Laurenz / Casas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Crafting the flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The three flows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tanda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supertanda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entire night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequence of songs and orchestras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energy reset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pattern: TTVTTM TTVTM TTTVM

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use these to control partner change frequencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TTVTM will encourage faster rotation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palate cleanser: chacarrera / salsa / swing

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only a good idea if enough people will actually dance it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Energy level flow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare a sawtooth energy pattern with a sinusoidal one&lt;br/&gt;
Sawtooth: doesn't allow for pallate cleansers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T1 T3 V5 T2 T4 M6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;TT Pairs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DiSarli/Rufino -&gt; Laurenz/Casas : Increasing strechiness&lt;br/&gt;
Fresedo -&gt; Troilo : Rythmic playfulness (gentle to more gripping)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crossing musical families between sets allows you to differentiate the adjacent sets&lt;br/&gt;
Avoid repeating musical familes (Canaro -&gt; OTV would be too much)&lt;br/&gt;
Alternating rythmic melodic within the supertanda covers your dancers tastes better&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about the thread between tango 1,2 and 4,5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Range of emotions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should be tighter in the beginning for newer dancers or people who just arrived&lt;br/&gt;
Should get wider toward the end to fill more of the milonga experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;br/&gt;
Canaro doesn't work pre-milonga, not enough build&lt;br/&gt;
DiSarli/Podesta into a Biagi would be too abrupt&lt;br/&gt;
No vals after a DiSarli/Podesta - they're too swirly and round (abrupt)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Cortinas&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should inspire motion, but in a vague way - Don't suggest swing / salsa&lt;br/&gt;
Should follow the previous tanda to prevent ruining the embrace-feeling they had&lt;br/&gt;
Length based on how long it will take the floor to clear (20s - 70s)C&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Changing the pattern&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last 30 minutes, or some defining point, she stops playing milongas and valses, just varies the energy levels of tangos&lt;br/&gt;
Reduces rotation and enhances flow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ending notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disabling trackpad-touch-to-click or bringing a mouse&lt;br/&gt;
Build double the sets you need for the time&lt;br/&gt;
Mixing - Saca chispas only good decaro milonga, has to be mixed with others&lt;br/&gt;
Tanda placards - nice but if you use them make sure you actually use them&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/25/music-for-djs.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/10/25/music-for-djs.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
